tutorspree.com 2018-12-26

# Privacy Policy | Wyzant Tutoring

**Last updated on May 15, 2018.**

This Privacy Policy is designed to help you understand how Wyzant, Inc. (“Wyzant” or “we”) collects, transmits, and stores information about our Users. The term “you” or “You” or “User” or “Users” shall refer to Students, Tutors or any person or entity who views, uses, accesses, browses or submits any content or material to the Service (defined below). This Privacy Policy is not a contract and does not create any legal rights. Providing your information is voluntary and your use of the Service (defined below) after the effective date of this document constitutes your acceptance of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to all the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy, do not use the Service.

## Information we collect

_Information you provide to us_

This Privacy Policy applies only to information we collect via the website www.wyzant.com (“Site”), online and mobile applications (“Apps”) (the Site and Apps collectively referred to as, the “Service”), email, telephone, electronic devices and other interactive services. In order to help you get the most out of our service, we collect User submitted personally identifiable information (“PII”) when you use the Service. For example we may collect information you provide when you create an account, create or edit your profile, upload content (photographs, essays, lessons, etc.), provide profile descriptions or comments, provide school information for a student, participate in a contest or promotion, participate in interactive features of the Service, connect or communicate with us via third party social media sites, send us an email, request customer support or otherwise communicate with us or communicate with others users through the Service. Such information may include your name, address, password, zip code, email address, and phone number for communication purposes. Information may be submitted to the Site or Apps or via telephone or email when communicating with a Wyzant representative. For students and parents, we may collect information related to your documentation of and payment for tutoring sessions; tutoring questions related to homework or your studies; teacher feedback of a student (once the parent provides consent for submission); and content you upload for the purposes of transmitting it to another user or for public display on the Site or Apps. For tutors, we may collect your Social Security number (SSN) or Federal Employer Identification number (FEIN) and date of birth, for tax purposes or to complete a background check; we also collect content you upload for purposes related to transmission to other users or public display on the Site or Apps. As detailed in the “Data Transmission and Storage” section below, we use Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption on any page of the Site where we ask you to submit personally identifiable information and encrypt all such information for safe storage in our system.

_Information we collect automatically_

We also gather non-PII when you use the Service, including type of browser you use, access time, pages viewed, your IP address; and we collect information about the computer or mobile device you use to access the Service, including without limitation operating system and unique device identifiers and mobile network information. This data is used to better understand and enhance the user experience on the Site and Apps. Wyzant may publish these statistics or share them with third parties without including PII. Some browsers allow you to indicate that you would not like your online activities tracked, using “Do Not Track” indicators (“DNT Indicators”), however we are not obligated to respond to these indicators. Presently we are not set up to respond to DNT Indicators. This means that we may use latent information about your online activities to improve your use of our Service, but such usage is consistent with the provisions of this Privacy Policy.

_Information we collect from other sources_

We may also obtain information from other sources and combine that with information we collect through the Service. For example, we may collect information about you from other users, identity verification services, credit bureaus, mailing list providers and publicly available sources. If you log into your account through sign-in services, like Facebook Connect or Google Authenticator, you provide Wyzant with permission to access certain information about you such as your Facebook User ID, user profile, friends list, user graph and profile picture. User generated content posted through certain social networking preferences (e.g. pages you “Like” or “Follow”) may be viewed by the general public. Accordingly, Wyzant cannot ensure the privacy of any PII included in such User generated content.

## Location information

When you use the Service, a location feature exists whereby it will automatically collect your geolocation information. In such event, the Service will use and share such location to enable users to determine which users in their network are nearby. Wyzant may also use location information to provide information and advertising to users. IF YOU WANT TO STOP THE AUTOMATIC COLLECTION OF YOUR LOCATION INFORMATION, YOU MAY DO SO BY USING THE PRIVACY SETTINGS ON YOUR BROWSER AND/OR ON YOUR DEVICE. FOR MOBILE APP USERS, YOU MAY ALSO UNINSTALL THE APP.

## Data transmission and storage

Wyzant uses industry-standard 128-bit SSL encryption when collecting and transmitting your information through the Site and the Wyzant network (collectively, the “System.”) Once information has been collected, we encrypt sensitive data in our database for added security. Wyzant also uses firewalls and hardware monitoring across our System to protect against unauthorized access. Unfortunately, even with these measures, Wyzant cannot guarantee the security of PII. By using the Service, you acknowledge and agree that Wyzant makes no such guarantee, and that you use the Service at your own risk.

## Financial information

If you elect to pay for tutoring lessons with a credit card, we will collect your name, credit card number, expiration date, and address information associated with the account. All financial information, other than credit card numbers, is stored and encrypted in our System in full compliance with the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard. We do not store credit card numbers.

If you are a tutor and elect to pay for a background check, we will collect credit card information to order a background check on your behalf. Payment information entered into our System solely to procure a background check will not be stored on our servers.

## Use of cookies

Wyzant uses cookies to help create a better user experience. A cookie is a small text file that is sent to your browser from a web server and may be stored on your computer’s hard drive. Wyzant uses cookies to better customize your experience on the Site based on User attributes like your location and account preferences. No personally identifiable information is stored in our cookies. While you may elect to disable or delete cookies from your browser at any time, please note that this action may limit your use of Wyzant services that require cookies. If you are interested in more information about tailored browser advertising and how you control cookies from being put on your computer to deliver tailored advertising, you may visit the Network Advertising Initiative’s website http://www.networkadvertising.org/ and/or the Digital Advertising Alliance’s website http://www.aboutads.info/choices/. You also can control advertising cookies from Google, by using its Ads Preference Manager. Please note that to the extent advertising technology is integrated into the Site, you may still receive advertisements even if you opt-out of tailored advertising.

## Use of Personally Identifiable Information

Wyzant may use PII or other personal information you specifically give to us: a) to provide services to you through the System, b) to process transactions and billing, c) for identification and authentication purposes, d) to communicate with you concerning the System, transactions, security, privacy and administrative issues relating to your use of the System, e) to improve your response to and interaction with the System, f) process and deliver contest and sweepstakes entries and rewards and verify eligibility; g) to do something you have asked us to do, or tell you of services that we think may be of interest to you; h) in the case of teacher feedback of a student, we will transmit it as you ask us to; i) personalize and improve the Service and deliver and display targeted advertisements on our Service, content or features in the Service and on other sites or apps; and j) to provide third party tutor-matching services an opportunity to provide you with information about tutors; and k) for administration of and troubleshooting regarding the System. Wyzant shares a minimum amount of information between tutors and students in order to facilitate the arrangement of tutoring sessions. We reserve the right to release non-personally identifiable information collected in aggregate, however. Third parties, including Facebook, may use cookies, web beacons, and other storage technologies to collect or receive information from our Site, apps and elsewhere on the internet and use that information to provide measurement services and target ads. If you wish to opt-out of the collection and use of information for ad targeting you can do so using the following links: http://www.aboutads.info/choices and http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/).

## Referrals

If you choose to use our referral service, to tell a friend about our Service, we will ask you for your friend’s email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the Site and up to two reminders. Wyzant, Inc. stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and reminders and tracking the success of our referral program. Your friend may contact us at support@wyzant.com to request that we remove this information from our database.

## Minors

This Service is not intended for use by children under 13 years of age.

Wyzant does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If you are under the age of 13, please do not provide your contact information or any other personally identifiable information to Wyzant. If you are the parent or legal guardian of someone under the age of 13 who may have provided us with information without your knowledge or consent, please contact us to have this information removed. All contact, including tutoring sessions, between a tutor and any minor should, of course, take place only in a supervised setting.

## Legal requests and business transfers

Wyzant may disclose personal information when we believe such action is necessary to comply with the law or enforce or apply our Terms of Service. In the event of a change in control of Wyzant’s business, personal information may be exchanged as part of a merger, sale, or other business transfer. If such a transfer makes a material change to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you of any changes.

## Your choices

Please remember to help keep the Site secure by never sharing your username or password. If you think your password may have been compromised, please change it immediately or contact Wyzant for additional assistance.

Wyzant may send you email communications periodically detailing new features or promotions on the Site. You may unsubscribe from these messages by using the link at the bottom of the email. We may also send you email messages about the status of your account or any notices as required by law. You may not opt-out of receiving these administrative emails so long as you continue to use this voluntary service. If you wish to terminate your account, please contact us.

## Your California Privacy Rights

California law permits users who are California residents to request and obtain from us once a year, free of charge, a list of the third parties to whom we have disclosed their personal information (if any) for their direct marketing purposes in the prior calendar year, as well as the type of personal information disclosed to those parties. If you are a California resident and would like to request this information, please submit your request in an email to privacy@wyzant.com.

## Privacy policy changes

Wyzant reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy, from time to time, due to modifications to the Site’s features and functionality. We will post any changes here and indicate the new effective date of the Privacy Policy at the top of the document. We encourage you to review the Privacy Policy for any updates while you are an active User of the Site.

## Users Outside the United States

The Site is hosted in the United States and is governed by United States law. If you are using the Site from outside the United States, please be aware that your information may be transferred to, stored and processed in the United States where our servers are located and our databases are operated. The data protection and other laws of the United States and other countries might not be as comprehensive as those in your country. By using the Site, you consent to your information being transferred to our facilities and to the facilities of those third parties with whom we share it as described in our Privacy Policy.

## Contact information

Questions regarding this Privacy Policy should be directed to support@wyzant.com or to the mailing address below.

Wyzant, Inc.  
1714 N Damen Ave  
Suite 3N  
Chicago, IL 60647
